

Alok Ranjan

Senior Manager - Concentrix, Gurgaon

Dear Sir,

I am interested in the role of **Senior Manager** in **PayUMoney**, one of the **leading financial service providers**. I have a total **13 years** of experience in **managing**, **developing & designing** different software products and providing technology solutions for a specific problem. I am currently employed at **Concentrix Global as a Senior Product Manager**. I believe that the skills and experience that I have gained at this position makes me an ideal candidate for the job of Product Manager. Also **fintech disruption** and **wealth management** is shaping this world in the coming years and I am keen to work in this next disruptive technology.

Furthermore, I have put my innovative ideas in building **UI page design of self explanatory workflow chatbot** for my telecom client, making it easy to use, so that he can easily create multiple workflows for the chatbot applying on his website so that his customer can easily get their answers to complaints, requests and queries.

My previous year achievement was **solving the problem with the BPO industry** with minimal resources available. Calculating **employees' productivity** in the BPO industry is tedious, delayed and inaccurate. I solved the problem by **building and designing a chrome extension using AppScript, browser databases** (**indexdb**) & **javascript**, which can track system state and capture events like button click, text input & url change, the live tracking for all the employees, as well as building a **beautiful dashboard using Highcharts.**

I have a **strong software development background** with **AI expertise.** After completing my Bachelor of Engineering from BMS Institute of Technologies, I started my career in a startup as a Software Engineer, then moving further, I came to Gurgaon, working in Concentrix as Technical Manager, I did my AI certification from **Great Lakes.**Further I did my **Product manager Certification** from Udemy where I learnt and applied the plan to draw on those methodologies and defined project on different metrics on project scheduling completion, issue tracking, and resource management tasks.

Sincerely,

Alok Ranjan

Alok Ranjan

Senior Manager - Concentrix, Gurgaon

E 311 Ace City, Greater Noida West, Noida (UP) -201306 (91) 7042915552 alokranjan04@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Concentrix, Gurgaon — Senior Manager

Oct 2015 - PRESENT

Managed and developed multiple internal projects for optimising the organisation resource, saved 20% of revenue .Presenting roadmaps to senior managers, Discussion with different tech and design teams Ensures major projects follow-up & established timeline. Developed and managed Angular-8 and Machine Learning projects providing Cognitive AI solutions to the customer.

CA Technology, Bangalore —Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2014 - Aug 2015

Designed & developed User Interface for enterprise mobile applications based on AngularJS,SASS,HAML,Bootstrap.

Accenture, Bangalore — Team Lead

Sept 2013 - Feb 2014

Developed and managed user authentication page for consumer complaint applications

Mobile Ops, Bangalore — Consultant

Feb 2013 - Aug 2013

Developed AngularJS project for Enterprise Mobile Application

ABB Global, Bangalore — Software Engineer

Mar 2012 - Feb 2013

Developed SAP based web application for asset management using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

WDC Technologies, Bangalore — UI Developer

April 2010 - Dec 2011

Developed and managed a telecom based product using HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap

Tarams Software Technologies, Bangalore — Software Engineer

July 2007 - April 2010

Developed telecom based product using Java, Struts, HTML, CSS, JS

SKILLS

Product Management.

Python3,Numpy, Pandas,Data Science, Machine Learning

AngularJS, Angular8,

ReactJS/React hooks,

Bootstrap3, Es6

AWARDS

2020 - Product Management
Certification - Udemy

2019 - Deep Learning Certificate from <u>Great Lakes</u> Certificates

2019 -Concentrix Employee of the year

2017 - <u>Javascript Codility</u> Awards -

Profile:

https://alokranjan04.github.i o/

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

EDUCATION

BMS Institute of Technology

July 2003- July 2007 Electrical & Electronics Engineering

G & H High School, Ranchi — 12th

July 1998 - July 2001 Physics, Chem, Maths, Eng, Economics

St Stephen's School, Hazaribag —10th

lune 1998i

PROJECTS

Workflow Chatbot

Built and designed the workflow bot project roadmap. I designed the flowchart model for creating workflow for the questions asked by different users and the bot answers according to the flow. The application was developed using Angular8 and RASA NLU. Being the Product Owner, I was responsible for the timely delivery of the project, also worked with the stakeholder for demos and change requests..

HR Management & Automation

In HR we have designed & developed an AI model through which the hiring and training costs of employees was reduced by 20% using predictive analysis. Determining which employees might leave the company first, applying **Logistic regression, Random Forest & Artificial Neural Network** on employees data on their work experience, employee satisfaction, work life balance, age group, etc, post & pre processing, achieved the predictive attrition percentage score for the given employees.

Source Code <u>Datasets</u>.

Marketing Ads Management

Targeting the ads to potential customers, increased audience engagement by 35% We grouped them according to their choices and showed the ads of their needs which increased the revenue of my organisation. Me and my team's role was to identify the behaviour of a customers by applying K-Means clustering and its optimal numbers using Elbow Method to perform market segmentation, understand build and train autoencoders using Keras to perform dimensionality reduction, understanding the intuition of Principle Component Analysis (PCA) to perform dimensionality reduction on customer details and group them accordingly so that marketers can launch targeted campaign tailored for their specific needs

Source Code Datasets .

Sales Forecasting

In Sales department of companies, my team has developed predictive modelling to predict weekly, monthly and yearly forecast trends which is being used for optimising the inventory management and minimising the product replacement which reduced wastage by 15% .Using .predictive modelling, time series forecasting, additive regression and Facebook Prophet to predict future weekly, monthly & yearly forecast trends based on the given data from 1100 stores on some features such as store promotions, store size, school and state holidays & types of products.

Source Code Datasets 1. Dataset 2 Dataset 3

Public Relations

in public relationship, me with my team built predictive models based on Natural Language Processing NLTK, performed sentiment analysis on social media post .Applying feature extraction using count vectors and applying Naive Based Classifiers to classify them in likelihood, prior likelihood & marginal likelihood, With balance datasets, train logistic regression, learn to make prediction on encoded text data to know whether the customers are happy or not without going through massive numbers of tweets or reviews.

Source Code Datasets